A long, long time ago
很久以前
Someone said that men were born free and equal
就有人说过人生而自由平等
All the men
所有的男人
And all women
也包括女人
All equal
全都平等
The rules of the game would be the same for everyone
这个规则就是人人平等
We would be on equal terms
芸芸众生皆平等
Life would be right
生命是公平的
But even if that was true
即便如此
a microsecond after birth
在你出生的一刹那
chance interferes
就得看看机会了
There are your parents
包括你的父母
your neighbourhood
你的邻居
your standard of living
生活条件
your health
健康
your size
身高
your appearance
还有你的外貌
As soon as the tyranny of chance begins to impose its law
若遇上暴政订下的法律（印度种姓制度）
we are no longer on equal terms
一切就都不平等
Chance changes everything
机会改变一切
Ultimately
最后
we do with what he gives us
就看你如何运用上天所赐
THE EXTRAORDINARY TRAVEL OF THE FAKIR
跟着IKEA衣橱去旅行
This is the story of Ajatashatru Lavash Patel
阿贾的故事就是这样
And here are the cards
看他如何打手中
that chance gave him
这副牌
The judge is a bastard!
法官太混蛋了!
It's a junk! A dirty cockroach!
真是垃圾! 连蟑螂都不如!
You are all idiots!
你们全都是白痴!
Who are you? What do you want?
你哪位? 你想怎样？
Dirty bug! You're a shit!
臭东西! 狗屎!
You're a shabby, you're too bad!
你个烂货，坏东西
Go away!
给我滚开!
Are you coming to beat us up?
你是来揍我们的吗？
- The other said that. - And then he beat us!
- 刚才有人也是这样说 - 然后就揍我们
I'm coming to tell a story
我是来讲故事的
- A story? - Yes
- 讲故事？ - 没错
What kind of story?
讲什么故事？
- A tragedy - tragedy？
- 悲剧 - 悲剧？
I prefer being beaten up
还是打我一顿吧
The judge sentenced you to 4 years in prison for juveniles
法官判你们关在少年监狱四年
You have time for a story
你有的是时间听故事
I can?
我可以开始了吧？
I was born in Bombay
我出生于孟买
in the very small district of Worli
是Worli的一个小地方
When I was a kid
我小的时候
I did not know anything about the rest of the world
我对外面的世界一无所知
Nothing
什么都不知道！
Siringh, the sheets are not ready yet?
Siringh,床单还没好吗？
You have to work faster!
手脚麻利点！
I am the only son of a wonderful, loving, hardworking woman
我是一个很了不起的女人的独子，她善良，勤劳
Siringh Lavash Patel
4 more bags of linen!
还要四麻袋！
It will be necessary to stay late!
这得搞到很晚！
Aja, stop your bad moves
阿贾，别再做坏事了
You must stop!
你必须收手！
Stop getting you into trouble
别再惹麻烦了
They will take you away
你会被抓走
I am a single mother. You understand?
我是个单亲妈妈，你懂吗？
You will be taken away from me
你会被带走
Stop doing bad things with your cousins
别再跟你表哥胡作非为了
If you are sent to prison
如果你被抓进局子
I will not come for you
我可不会去捞你
I will not come
不信等着瞧
Eat
吃啊
You are too skinny
你太瘦啦
You must be strong
如果你想让我有朝一日
if you want me to take you to Paris one day
带你去巴黎，现在就得吃得壮壮的
Eat
吃
Eat!
吃啊！
Come on, you're too skinny. Eat, Moohini
快吃啊，你太瘦啦，吃啊，Moohini
Eat!
吃！
When I was small
小时候
my mother said I did not have a father
我妈妈说我没有爸爸
She claimed that I was a kind of miracle
他声称我就是个奇迹
arrived as if by magic
就像魔术变出来的
obviously
很显然
I did not believe it
我当然不信
- Mom, it's him? - No！
- 妈妈，是他吗？ - 才不是
I need the sheets of Maharaja and Presidency hotels
快给我凯撒跟晶华酒店得床单
Now! Quick!
现在就要，快！
Why is it so long?
怎么那么慢？
Hurry!
快啊！
Mom@@
妈@@
- it's him? - No！
- 是他吗？ - 不是！
It's him?
是他吗？
No, it's not him!
不是，不是他！
Stop asking me the same question!
别再一直问这个问题
You do not have a father
你没爸爸
You are very beautiful
大帅锅
My little man
小男子汉
Let's review the continents. The continents are Europe@@
我们复习世界地图，这是欧洲大陆@@
Before school, my world was very small
上学前，我得世界很小
We did not have TV or internet
我们没有电视或网络
My world was expanding
从阿土表哥到阿宾表哥家
from my cousin Bhatuk to my cousin Bheem's home
就是我得世界
Nothing else existed for me
除此之外就没啦
So while discovering the rest of the world, I learned a staggering thing@@
所以当我发现有其他让我咋舌的事情@@
Mom!
妈妈
I was poor
我真是穷
- Are we poor? - No
- 我们穷吗？ - 不！
Yes!
就是穷！
Why do you say we are not poor?
为啥你说我们不穷？
I've been in school. I know things
我都上学啦，也懂事啦
We are very poor
我们好穷
We are rich because we are together
我们能在一起就不贫穷
It does not make us rich
那也没让我们有钱
We will do other exams. This is very serious
我们还要做几次补考测验，得认真对待
I am sorry@@
很遗憾@@
I understand
我明白
And then one day
然后有一天
at the doctor
在诊所
I made an extraordinary discovery
我有了一个惊天地泣鬼神得发现
It's the same model
都长得一样
with different colors
只是颜色不同
This one is the best
这个是最好的
And they have names that are too cool
每个都有很酷得名字
The Vinterdimma collection
温特玛系列
the Rostig Lördag collection
周末系列
the Bergman Bögart collection
柏格曼系列
Mom, when I'm very, very rich
妈妈，当我非常非常有钱得时候
I will have a Borgshot room
我要一个这样得房间
Moohini, in the living room, we will have the Scötken coffee table
Moohini，我们要在客厅摆一张Scötken得咖啡桌
My favorite collection is@@
我最喜欢得系列是@@
the Djup Sömn collection
深度睡眠系列
special edition Trädtoppar
尤其是树梢版
The Khoobsurut collection,signed Ajatashatru
阿贾设计得美丽系列
The Sundaryat collection, signed by the famous Ajatashatru
著名阿贾设计的Sundaryat系列
And the Taranchalah collection
还有Taranchalah系列
signed by the extraordinary Ajatashatru
都出自杰出的阿贾之手
Stop doing that
别闹啦
- It was my father? - No！
- 那是我爸爸吗？ - 不是！
That year, two things became clear
那年，我终于明白了两件事
One: I was poor
一，我是真得穷
Two: I did not want to be poor anymore
二，我真的不想再受穷
Excuse me
借过
Faster!
再快点！
Here
给我
Hurry up!
赶快！
Quick!
快！
It's very heavy
好重啊
Approach!
成功啦！
Come see the famous Aja!
大名鼎鼎得阿贾
Over the years
那些年
we did all kinds of magic tricks
我们玩了各种花式骗人魔术
Magic show!
多神奇的魔术！
Levitation
悬浮
Illusions
冥想
Psychic surgery
挖心术
My friends
朋友们
This is your first trip to India?
是第一次来印度玩吗？
First trip to India?
第一次来印度啊？
Great
真不错
More and more, magic was only a small part of our activities
魔术表演越来越成为我们诸多名堂中的一小部分
We won that?
有啥收获？
Next time, 40%
下一次，四成
Not 40%!
四成不行
It's my neighborhood
这我的地盘
Hello
嗨
Sorry for the delay, I was stuck at work by a dinosaur@@
抱歉迟到啦，工作简直太忙了
Mom, I want you to eat, the doctor says you have to eat
妈，你要吃点，医生说你一定得吃饭
Aja@@
阿贾@@
Mom, you must be strong for me to take you to Paris
妈，你一点要强壮一点才能带你去巴黎
We do not have money to go to Paris
我们哪有钱去巴黎
I'm going to take you to Paris
我会带你去巴黎
Who will take care of Moohini?
谁来照顾牛啊?
Moohini is sacred, you're not supposed to take care of her
Moohini是神牛，不用你照顾
She is the one who has to take care of you
她得照顾你才是
We will go to Paris
我们去巴黎吧
Tonight you're eating
今晚你得吃饭
Yes, Aja
好吧阿贾
But before we can go to Paris
但就在去巴黎之前
the bad news has fallen
噩耗传来
A concern, Moohini?
怎么啦，Moohini？
Her heart@@
她心脏@@
had stopped
停止了跳动
- So, she never went to Paris? - No
- 就是，她没有去成巴黎？ - 没有
Chance did not help me keep that promise
机会没有帮我履行这个承诺
My father's name was Pierre-André Martin
我们父亲得名字是Pierre-André Martin
He was French, from Paris
法国人，来自巴黎
A street artist, like me
街头艺人，跟我一样
He had written to my mother hundreds of sublime love letters
他给我妈写过几百封凄美动人得情书
One said
其中提到
that if my mother's parents allowed her to marry him
如果我外公外婆同意我妈嫁给他
she had to go to Paris, at the top of the Eiffel Tower
她就去巴黎埃菲尔铁塔顶
Every Sunday，he would wait for her
每周日都会在那等她
If he was not there
如果他不在那
she had to fold the letter shaped plane
她就把信折成纸飞机
and throw it to the city
从塔上扔下来
He would lead her to him by magic
它能靠魔法带她找到他
I borrowed a few rupees from Giri
我跟Giti借了点钱
We went to Paris
准备去巴黎
Go, find another family
去吧，另找个主人
Watch over me, Moohini!
保佑我，Moohini!
Go away!
去吧
Carrying only the ashes of my mother
只带上我妈的骨灰
A passport and a counterfeit 100
一本护照，还有一张100块假欧元
I made the long trip to Paris
长途跋涉到巴黎
to find my father
去找我爹
- This is your first trip to Paris? - ah, yes
- 第一次来巴黎玩吗？ - 哦，是
Perfect
太好啦
You want a taxi?
要出租车吗？
- That's why@@ - Please, follow me
- 这就是为啥我@@ - 跟我走
Where do you want to go first?
先去哪？
Some want to see the Eiffel Tower
一般都先去看铁塔
An obvious choice
首选
But some dream of Montmartre,others go to the Louvre
但也有人想去Montmartre，也有去罗浮宫的
Others at the Champs-Élysées
还有人去香榭大道
Paris is the most beautiful city in the world
巴黎是世界上最美的城市
You will see everything for the first time
你会大开眼界
The Arc de Triomphe for the first time
凯旋门
The gardens of Luxembourg
卢森堡花园
It's going to be the best day of your life
这将是你一生中最美好的一天
You will tell your children and your grandchildren
可以跟你的子子孙孙说说
You're in luck
你是多么幸运
I do not know if there is Uber at your place
不知道你们那有没有优步
but in Paris, they kill the job
但在巴黎他们直接砸了的哥的饭碗
They steal our job. It's ugly
抢走我们的工作，太恶毒
Uber, it's hell
操蛋的优步
I have to do a second job on weekends
害我周末还要去兼职
What are you doing?
那你兼职做什么？
Uber
优步呗
What does the government do?
这是啥政府啊？
And then, I understood
然后，我发现
that this man was stealing from me
这家伙想黑我
Gustave was a thief
Gustave是个小偷
He was terrific
他很有一套
Polite, playful conversation
有礼貌，能说会道
Very endearing personality
平易近人
I should have been furious, but I was not
本来要发飙的,但还是忍住了
Because for the first time in my life
毕竟这是我平生第一次
it was me, the rich tourist
就充一回观光客
Aja, do you have my number?
阿贾，我电话号码记住啦吧？
Yes, absolutely
当然了
Here
给
Thank you very much
非常感谢
Gustave, it's an honor@@
Gustave，认识你...
A privilege to know you
真是三生有幸
No, all the honor is for me
不，应该是我的幸运
See you soon
再见啦
Such a beautiful city
那么美丽的一个城市
And so many choices
充满着无数的选择
Where did you go first?
那你先去了哪里？
At my favorite furniture store
当然是我最爱的IKEA
Hedar och Skogar
森林和雪茄
The best sofa in the world
世界上最棒的沙发
The extraordinary Vinterdimma collection
非凡的温特玛系列
The cushions Döva Tidvatten
Döva Tidvatten 坐垫
The elegant Sharton collection
优雅的Sharton系列
The Brandchat collection
Brandchat系列
- Have you ever been in love? - No
- 谈过恋爱吗？ - 没有
You@@
你呢
did it happen to you?
谈过吗？
I am 13 years old
我才13岁
- He likes Naveena - Not true
- 他喜欢Naveena - 才没有
She is 16 years old and he loves her
她16岁了，他很爱她
Shut up!
别瞎说！
He does not like it?
你说不是吗？
Yes, he likes it!
没错，他就是爱她
Do not go, or I'll hit you
别乱说，不然揍你
Stop
好啦
It's nothing
没关系
It does not matter if you like it
如果你喜欢也没什么的
- I do not like it! - OK，OK
- 我才没有 - 好吧,好吧
Short
不管怎样
Due to a unique geomagnetic field
在巴黎,那独特的
love in Paris
恋爱氛围
is ten times stronger than elsewhere
比其他任何地方要强十倍
For centuries
几个世纪以来
love in Paris inspires many books
巴黎之恋启发出了好多著作
movies, songs, poems, paintings
还有电影,歌曲,诗歌,绘画
- You knew it? - No
- 知道吗？ - 不知道
What did you do in school?
那上学学啥啦？
We do not go to school
我们没上学的
You do not go to school@@
你们不上学@@
Honey, sorry to come home late from work
亲爱的对不起,我下班回家晚了
the traffic was crazy
交通太糟糕
I promised to make the meal, do not be angry
我说过我做晚饭的,别生气
I put in the kitchen,it will be delicious
下厨包在我身上，保准你爱吃
Excuse me, I have to test the salon before buying it
不好意思，购买之前我不得预演一下嘛
A salon is not just a design
不光是买设计
it is especially what we feel
买的是感觉
when we enter
置身其中的感觉
Honey, where are my car keys?
亲爱的，我车钥匙呢？
Did you see them?
看到我车钥匙了吗？
My God!
天啊！
My boss drives me crazy
老板快把我逼疯了
You feel under pressure, darling?
亲爱的，亚历山大？
How'd you do this to me?
你怎么可以这样对我？
With my own brother?
跟我亲哥哥？
What? no, I am not his brother
啥玩意？！不，我不是你哥哥
Your brother and I, we love each other
你哥哥跟我，你情我愿
We will live in Guatemala
我们要移居危地马拉
Not that@@
不要@@
Not in Guatemala!
别去危地马拉！
I am pregnant
我怀孕了
What?
什么?
Because of this unique geomagnetic field
这样独特的气氛
between Marie and me,it stuck right away
让玛利跟我立刻有了感觉
Why would a beautiful American woman be interested in an Indian fakir?
一个米国正妹怎么会爱上你这个印度骗子？
I do not know
我也不晓得
But chance seemed finally to be on my side
但机遇似乎最终眷顾了我
That day
那天
Marie listened to me
玛利倾听了我
while I told him about India
关于印度形形色色的
Colors and sounds
颜色啊，声音啊
Clothes, tastes
服饰啊，美食啊
Its hundreds of languages
上百种方言
His religions, his customs
宗教，习俗
The vastness of Bombay
孟买的一切
and the charm of my little neighborhood
还有我温馨的左邻右舍
It's like that in deep India
恍若置身印度
I've got to go
我该走了
Since leaving Chicago
我离开芝加哥后
I have a boring job in an American consulting firm
在一家叫威尔森和威廉的美国顾问公司工作
called Wilson & Williams
工作枯燥乏味
Why did you leave Chicago?
那为啥离开芝加哥?
I left with my best friend, Rose
为了跟我的闺蜜 Rose 一起
My parents hate her.She would have a bad influence
我父母很讨厌她，担心我被她带坏
Does she?
会吗?
才不会
No
My parents blame her for leaving my future husband at the altar
我父母责怪她影响我找男朋友
Take this newspaper article
收好这个剪报
Why?
为什么？
It's like the promise
当做一个信物
we'll meet again
相信我们会再见面
I think this is very very important to me
这对我意义重大
And I keep your pen
我还保留着你的笔
How did you@@
你怎么拿到的...
See you tomorrow
明天见
I dunno@@
我不@@
To the Eiffel tower?
还在埃菲尔铁塔？
7 oclock
晚上7点
Yes, but it's not a date
好吧，但这不算是约会喔
Never date?
都不约会？
No, I don't date ever
不，我从不约会
Here in Paris, we usually do it on the cheek
在巴黎通常是亲脸颊
I am so sorry
对不起
It's OK
没关系啦
I was thinking maybe I could become a lesbian
我一直在想我，我也可以成为女同
Why?
为啥？
Why not?
为啥不行？
I mean you do not like sleeping with women and@@
我是说，你不喜欢跟女人睡并且...
from I heard that pretty big part of being lesbian
据我所知那是当女同很重要的事
I could learn to like it
我可以学啊
You know, I hated eating broccoli when I was a kid
就像我小时候讨厌吃花椰菜
now, I eat broccoli all the time
现在不也经常吃嘛
And it's such a cool life style
这种生活太酷了
Rose, you are 27 years old
Rose,你也27啦
I think you would know by now if you were lesbian
我觉得你如果是女同，早就应该知道
What?
咋了？
I may have met someone
我遇到个人
Finally!
终于！
Wait,wait@@
等等
Is it a girl?
是个女孩？
Since having no money
因为身无分文
I choiced to stay there overnight
我决定在IKEA过夜
Exhausted by my trip
因为旅途劳顿
I quickly fell asleep
我很快就睡着了
Unfortunately
不幸的是
I was mistake
我错了
Chance was still not on my side
机会完全没有在我这边
Not at all
完全不在
In the middle of the night
就在半夜
among the 2,000 pieces of furniture@@
在2000多件家具中@@
This one
就那件
And 15 different wardrobes
还有15个壁橱中
Mine was the one they have to pick
偏偏选中了我这个
Chance was definatlely not mine
机会确实不在我这
welcome in England
英国欢迎你
Where we are? Where are we going?
我们在哪？要去哪？
In the land of milk and honey
要去牛奶和蜂蜜的国度
Milk and honey?
牛奶和蜂蜜？
- In London  - In London?
- 在英国 - 英国?
Yes, where everything grows in abundance
是啊，富饶之城
cars, houses, jobs
汽车，房子，工作
And beer. Full of beer
还有啤酒，到处都是啤酒
We dono't drink beer
我们不喝啤酒
We hate that
我们讨厌啤酒
Are you illegal immigrant?
你们是偷渡客？
and you are not?
你不是？
No, I am a tourist
我说我是来观光的你信吗？
A tourist?
游客？
Traveling in a wardrobe?
到衣柜观光？
Yes, you are doing the famous wardrobe tour
没错，传说中的衣柜游
wardrobes are great legroom
衣柜豪华舱啊
I travel to Bora Bora in a business class wardrobe
我是坐壁橱商务舱去大溪地
Really, I'm a tourist
不骗你，我真的是旅游的
We are all tourists
我们都是旅游的
I have my passport, I come from India
我有护照，从印度来的
See
瞧
- Somalia  - Somalia？
- 索马里 - 索马里？
We have been travelling for 18 months
我们已经长途跋涉18个月了
We've been walking for weeks and weeks
徒步好几个星期了
actually,in the begaining there many more of us
实际上，刚开始我们有好多人
In Libya
在利比亚
We have been attacked by bandits
我们遇到强盗袭击
Then the smugglers sank our boat
我们的偷渡船沉了
2 miles from the Italian coast
在离意大利海岸2英里的海上
Only a few that meet today reached Italain shore
只有少数人游上意大利岸
Then we crossed the French border
之后我们穿过发过边境
Now，it's only five of us left
现在，就剩我们5个人了
Why would you go through all of this?
你们为何遭这般苦难？
Our families have been displaced by war
战争让我们流连失所
We must send them money to them. They are starving
我们必须赚钱寄回去养家，否则他们就得饿肚子
isn't it the same with you?
你不也是这样的吗？
I'm a tourist
我是个游客
There is an African proverb that says:
非洲有个谚语，说
"He who swallows coconuts
吞椰子的人
"has the ***"
翻译也没听懂
I do not see that link
没听过
Not the event
无所谓啦
I just love the proverb
我就是喜欢这句话
Why do we stop?
怎么停了？
What is happening?
啥情况？
- Dogs@@ - Which dogs?
- 狗 - 什么狗？
Let's run
跑吧
Borders police
边防站
I have my passport
我有护照
Never show it
千万别拿出来
Go go go
快快快
Do not move!
站住
Police, stop!
警察,站住！
Good God!
额滴个神啊！
Moohini? You're not supposed to watch over me?
神牛，不是说好保佑我的吗？
Stop!
站住
To the left!
在左边！
I can not go home
我不能被遣返回国
You, stop!
你，站住！
This way!
这边！
Do not move
别动
Wait
I am Ajatashatru Lavash Patel
我叫阿贾
a famous Indian fakir
印度有名的法基(就是骗子啦)
Good for your mouth
滚犊子
And my friend, I'll do it@@
我的朋友，我会让他
disappear
消失
and reappear far away
然后在很远的地方出现
Yes, I must see
表演一下让我看看
Copperfield, where is he?
科波菲尔魔术大师，他人呢？
I dream!
真像做梦一样！
I go there, take care of the fakir
我去那边，你盯住这骗子
Come on, my bunny
来吧，小白兔(魔术师的道具)
No more bundles
别再耍花样
I said "No More clutter"
叫你别"耍花样"
Let's go
走
A little last
再来一次
Put them back
快铐回去
Like this?
这样吗?
No, you need these documents for everyone
不是的，每个人都要填表
Sir!
长官!
It is a mistake!
这是个误会!
I am not part of this group
我不是一起的偷渡客
This man is right
他说得对
He tells the truth
他说的是实话
No one in this group is in this group
我们这些人没人是偷渡客
Please, I have to go back to Paris
求你了,我得赶回巴黎
Houdini, with me
魔术大师,跟我来
Sir!
长官
- It's yours?  - Yes
- 这是你的? - 是的
What are you doing? That's the passport!
你干嘛? 那是我的护照!
It was fake
假护照
No! It wasn't
不! 不是假的
You have talent:You make people disappear
你有天分把人变消失
I make fake passports disappear
而我专变假护照
But that's my passport!
可那是我的真护照!
Let's not dwell on the past, should we? What about this?
我们别再纠缠不清了,看这个
Real?
真的?
Fake? Fake, real, fake, real...
假的? 假的,真的,假的,真的...
- False  - Fake, yep.
- 假的 - 假的,好吧
Here... is your pen,
这是你的笔
your photos
照片
and the...
还有...
You can even keep this love letter from your father.
你可以带上你老爸的情书
Very well written.
写得不错
Poignant
很感人
He kept that bullshit real.
说得比唱得好听
Now,
现在
here is a map
这有张地图
of the world.
世界地图
This...
这是
is England.
英国
There is no map.
可这没地图
Yes, yes. Usually we have a map here.
是的是的,通常我们这有张地图
Bear with me.
听我说完
You are not allowed
你不允许
here. Yes?
到这,知道吧?
You,
你
not allowed
不允许
here.
到这里
Do you understand English?
你懂英语吗?
- We have been speaking English  - Answer the question is part of our protocol.
- 我们曾经讲英语 - 回答问题是例行程序
Yes!
好吧!
Where do you...
你在哪@@
you...
你
where
哪里
do you want to go?
要去哪里?
Where?
哪里?
- Paris!  - Ah, Pa--ri--s.
- 巴黎! - 啊,巴--黎
If we send you back to France,
如果我们把你送回法国
you'll be right back here next week with your little Hangö face
你一周后一准带着苦大仇深的脸再又回来
and a brand new name
换个名字
on a brand new fake passport.
换本假护照
But I don't want to come to England.
但我不想来英国
Is it the weather?
因为天气吗?
No!
不是!
You lost. Gerard!
那你惨了,杰拉德!
I'm going to ask you to sign your statement.
我让你签一个声明
But I've not made any statement yet.
可我没做任何声明
I know, I know.
好吧,好吧
Oh...
嗯...
Oh, you are serious. Rights, okay... Hm...
嗯,你态度蛮诚恳,好吧...嗯...
Yep, go on then.
好,继续
I admit that I stayed back in the Swedish furniture store.
我承认,我待在Swedish家具店
I was afraid they might think I'm a thief.
我担心他们把我当小偷
I hid in a wardrobe.But that was my only crime.
我躲在衣柜里,那算是我唯一犯的错
My mother is still there, in a vase.
我妈还在那呢,在罐子里
She is dead. Then I met Marie.
我妈去世了,之后我遇到了Marie
You are not taking any notes!
你根本没在听!
No, no. I prefer my statement.
是的,我更想听你的声明
Let me let you in to a secret.
跟你说个秘密
We have a charter plane...
我们有班包机...
booked for Spain,
是去西班牙的
but not a single illegal here is actually from there.
但没有从那来的偷渡客
Can...Can you please just send me back to Paris?
拜托啊,可以送我回巴黎吗?
Can I sing you the answer?
听不懂吗? 我唱给你听
* I have a charter for Spain *
* 我有架去西班牙的包机*
* And I need to fill that plane *
*我不让它能空着回去*
* You are a persona non grata *
*刚好你不受欢迎*
* You need to go to Barcelona *
*你就得飞到巴塞罗那*
* Once you're there *
*到那里*
* Please refrain *
*别想*
* From coming back by bus or train *
*坐着大巴或火车再回来*
No, no...no. That's not possible!
不,不不不,这根本不可能!
I have to go back to Paris.
我得回巴黎
* I'm gonna need you to sing that *
*我希望你再唱一遍*
What?
啥玩意?
Sing it. We're singing!
唱出来,预备...起!
* Marie's waiting at the Eiffel Tower *
*Marie在埃菲尔铁塔等着我*
* It's not a date *
*虽然不是约会*
* But I will bring flowers *
*但我还是送花给她*
* I'm begging you for your empathy *
*我求求你,行行好*
* Help me go back to... *
*把我送回...
* Pa--ri--s *
*巴--黎
* Your protests *
*抗议
* Are in vain *
*无效
* You can visit Andalusia *
*你只能去西班牙Andalusia
* Malaga, Seville, Segovia *
*Malaga, Seville还有Segovia
* Eat tapas with your best pal *
*享用小吃
* Even play tennis with Nadal *
*跟Nadal打网球
I don't play tennis.
我不打网球
This old man shakes his fan.
这位老先生挥着扇子
Send him to his native land.
把他送回国
These kids love churros.
这小鬼爱吃西班牙油条
Off they go to Burgos.
还有嘻哈,就在Burgos
This beauty looks like Shakira.
这位金发美女多像Shakira
People just love Barcelona.
谁不喜欢巴塞罗那
Shakira is from Colombia.
Shakira是哥伦比亚天后
Hips do not "mentira" (lie).
屁股骗不了人
She should go back to "su casa" (her home).
她应当回Su casa 老家
How many times must I explain,"You're all going to Spain!"
还要我解释多少遍,"你们全都得去西班牙!"
Papers?
证件呢?
Step aside.
先到一边
Come on.
下一位
Papers.
证件
No papers.
没证件
- Are you Spanish?  - No.
- 你是西班牙人? - 不是
Anyone here from Spain?
里面有西班牙人吗?
Does anyone here actually have any connection whatsoever to Spain?
里面跟西班牙沾上边的有吗?
What about you?
你呢?
I am British.
我英国人
I am Swiss.
我是瑞士的
"Maigaru, fina buda"
额的个神啊
And we have arrived in Barcelona,
我们到了巴塞罗那
there was a huge,huge war going on
发生了一场战争
between Captain Smith
是史密斯上尉
and Inspector Fernandez.
跟Fernandez警督
- Respectfully, UK would not tolerate its loss flouted by your migrants  - Respectfully, the Spanish kingdom will not have your migrants...
- 我们英国不会收容你的移民 - 西班牙不会收留你的移民
You mistake...
你有没搞错...
We will not suffer the consequences of your lax approach to border control.
我们不会因为你们乱来而承担这种麻烦
- Stupid cow!  - Tú boogers!
- 笨猪 - 废物!
We ended up as hostages to this dispute.
我们成了这场战争的皮球
We were prisoners.
最后坐了牢
Please tell me you are calling...
后悔了吧?
Because you feeling guilty for having sex on your first date,
第一次约会就上床会有罪恶感
which you insisted is not an official date, which remind you most definitely is.
就算你坚持不承认是约会,我还是这样认为
Unfortunately, not,
很不幸,你错了
given that it's impossible to have sex with someone who never show up.
就算那样,那连个人影都没见跟谁上床
Technically, that's not true.
不会的吧
With apps like Snapchat,you can send really hot pictures of your...
用微信发个你的热图...
Rose.
And then he warps it out and takes a picture of his...
他也可以拍一张他的...
Rose!
You messed up.
是你自己搞砸了
Why?
为什么这么说?
It's like your aborted marriage.
就像泥流产的婚姻
Don't go there.
别提这个好吗
Yes, yes, I'm...I'm going there.
没错,我就是想说说这个
Don't go there.
别说啦
Too late, I'm already there.
我都说到这了,就直截了当吧
You over think things,you complicate everything.
是你想太多,把事情搞复杂化
You're a stick-in-the-mud.
你真是自讨无趣
Ever since the marriage fiasco,
自从你婚姻失败,你就变成
you've become the most boring person in the world
世界上最无趣的人
I mean, relax!
听我说,放松自己
Live a little. You're in Paris, for Christ's sake!
享受一下生活,你可是在巴黎啊!
OK.
好吧
You should become a lesbian, like me.
不然你学我,当女同
You're not lesbian.
你不是女同
Yes, I am.
真的,我是
It's all about the life style, Marie.
热爱生活的方式有很多种,Marie
I'll think about it.
我想想吧
Excuse me, I'm sorry. Um...Can I ask you something?
不好意思,可以请教一下?
My phone just die.
我手机刚没电了
Is this the...the way to the Trocadero metro station?
去Trocadero地铁站走这边吗?
- Ah, yeah  - Yeah?
- 啊,是的 - 真的?
Ah, thank you, that's great.
啊,谢谢,太好了
Yeah, just that way.
没错,就这边
- Where are you from?  - America.
- 你哪里人? - 美国
Look at them.
你看他们
How's life fair?
怎么会这样?
How can it be that the same people always get all the chances in life?
机会怎么总是眷顾这些人?
There is no such thing as chance.
你说的机会根本就不存在
Karma is everything.
都是因果轮回
Karma is the fate we deserve.
这都是前世造的孽
I must have been a real asshole in another life.
我上辈子肯定是个大混球
Karma
因果报应
The media didn't cover the story.
媒体没有报道我们
No one seem to care.
也没人鸟我们
We were stuck.
我们就这样被困住了
So, what did you do, dude?
之后呢,怎么办了兄弟?
I worked on my karma...
践行我的因果报应...
So I could get back to Paris.
这样才能回到巴黎
Your name. Which one is your name?
你名字,哪一个是你名字?
There are 4 different names.
这有四个不同名字
Thank you, everyone.
谢谢大家
Aw, I need some new ideas for our cosmetics market.
嗯,请大家提出对化妆品市场的想法
And, as of Monday,
从周一开始
Marie will be our new V.P. Marketing.
Marie将上任我们新的行销主管
Congratulations.
恭喜你啊
Some more cheese.
再多点乳酪
That is...way too much.
太多了
- Yeah, but eh, we are celebrating.  - Yeah.
- 是啊,呃,值得庆祝一下嘛 - 好吧
So, yes...
嗯,对了...
- Cheers.  - Cheers.
- 干杯 - 干杯
To your well-deserved promotion, and...
为你当之无愧的升职,还有...
And?
还有什么?
And, I decided to move to Paris on a permanent bases.
还有,我决定在巴黎定居
Wow! Um...
哇! 嗯...
Permanent...Wow.
定居...哇
That's great. That's so...That's great.
太棒了,那真是...太棒了
Peter's moving to Paris.
Peter要搬去巴黎
That's great.
那不错啊
Yeah. Yeah, it's great.
是,是的,挺不错
He is...He's great.
他也很棒
Rose, my life is perfect.
Rose,我的生活挺完美
It's absolutely perfect.
当然是百分百完美
Did you know that
你知道吗?
he carried me in his arms
我逛街时伤到脚
for several blocks because I hurt my foot?
他硬是抱着我走了好几条街
And then, he proceeded to massage my foot
之后还帮我按摩脚
with a god-like healing touch. And,
犹如上帝般的治愈,而且
whenever we go to a restaurant,
当我们去酒店时
He speaks to the waiter in their native tongue.
他跟服务员用母语讲话
Who is her?
她是谁?
Can we talk about this tomorrow?
我们明天再聊好吗?
Yep.
好吧
I think I may not be a lesbian.
我终于了解也许我不是女同
Karma.
因果报应
It works
灵验了
every time.
每次都是
In that confined space,
在这个狭小的空间
I felt the uncontrollable urge to write
我按奈不住写作的冲动
the story of Master Deva.
写下Deva大师的故事
A very wise and wonderful man
一个在坐牢是认识的
I met when I ended up in jail.
非常聪慧又了不起的人
You've been to jail?
你坐过牢?
Yes, मेरे दोस्त। (my friend).
是的,兄弟
And I was even younger than you.
那时我比你还小
I was confined in a tiny cell, with no bed and no window.
我被关在一个很小的囚室,没床没窗户
Bastard!
你这混蛋
You'll go to hell!
你会下十八层地狱
Your mother must be stupid to have you this garbage!
你妈妈生你这垃圾儿子一定是有病
You're dirt!
脑袋装大便
You sewerage rat.
你个下水道的老鼠
You swine!
大笨猪
You cockroach!
臭蟑螂
You jerk! Get me out of here!
你个混球! 把我放出去!
I want to go home.
我要回家
After couple of weeks,
过了几个礼拜
I was driven crazy by hunger,
我被饥饿折磨疯了
solitude
孤单
and the fact I thought my mother would never want to see me again.
担心我妈不会再想见到我
No...!!!
不要!!!
Please help me, God!
天啊,帮帮我!
Please!
救我!
For as long as I was in the jail,
被关了很久
I was wonder what my cousins were doing.
我不知道我表哥在外做什么
How long are you in for?
你被关了多久?
I don't know.
不知道
I don't even have a window.
连个窗户都没有
I have a window. I could tell you what I see.
我有窗,我可以告诉你我看到的
Children are playing with a ball in the street.
孩子们在街上玩球
That's market day.
今天有集市
Traders are setting up stalls.
商户们都支起了摊位
A woman is sunbathing in the balcony.
阳台有个晒成古铜色的女人
A mother is taking water to the children who are playing.
一个妈妈在给贪玩的孩子喂水
They are fighting who gets to drink first.
孩子们在为谁先喝争抢
The boys and girls are playing cricket with sticks and...
男孩跟女孩们在一起玩板球
I hear music in the distance...
我听到远远的音乐声...
making a mess all around!
喧杂又热闹
There is a young man with a light beard with bright clever eyes.
有个年轻的胡须男,眼睛又大又亮
He's in love.
他在恋爱中
Can you hear that bird singing?
你听到小鸟的歌唱了吗?
What does it look like?
它看起来什么样子?
Blue, red and yellow feathers.
有蓝色红色和黄色的羽毛
His eyes are like tiny olives.
它的眼睛像小橄榄一样圆
You are getting out now.
你现在可以出去了
Master Deva?
Deva大师?
I'm getting out now.
我现在要出去了
For the longest of time,
很久以后
I thought I would never meet Master Deva again.
我以为今生不会再见到Deva大师了
Mama!
妈妈!
Soon,
很快
I was back on the streets,
我又回到了街上
with my cousins.
跟我表弟一起
Aja?
阿贾
Master Deva?
Deva大师?
Aja, is that you?
阿贾,是你吗?
You're blind?
你是盲人?
Yes, I am blind. But it doesn't matter...
是啊,我是个盲人,但没关系...
His eyes couldn't see,
他的双眼看不到
but it didn't prevent him from seeing with imaginations.
但这不妨碍他通过想象洞察世界
Out of the darkest moment of my life,
在我最黑暗的日子里
Master Deva created the most beautiful lesson.
Deva大师给我上了最美好的人生课
Did you tell Alfredo I was upset?
跟Alfredo说了我很烦吗?
Yes, I told him you were very, very...
是的,我告诉他你...
very upset. Yes.
超级烦
Does he know I'm waiting for him in Paris?
他知道我在巴黎等他吗?
Yes.
是的
The re-shoot is only one day.
重拍只需一天时间
That's a lie.
骗人
Well, he promised,
嗯,他承诺的
Just one day.
只要一天
Yet, and Matthew calls
Matthew打来电话
and sent you three emails and twenty-two texts.
说给你发了三封邮件,发了22个手机短信
Well, may be next time he won't forget to thank me at the Golden Globes.
嗯,让他记着下次得了金球奖别忘感谢我
OK.
好的
Um, and then there is Mr. Burton he needs to know if you read the fairy tale script
还有,Burton先生问您看过通话的剧本没
and if you would consider playing the role... of the... witch.
您是否考虑出演...巫婆
A witch.
巫婆喔
Yes
是的
The witch
是巫婆
Everyone out!
全给我滚出去!
I hate Rome.
我讨厌罗马
You don't need a gun.
你用不着用枪的啊
Why are you half naked in my trunk?
你为啥半裸着藏在我箱子里?
I had only my shirt to write on.
我能在上面写作的只有这件上衣
I couldn't get it back on.
我可以穿上
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
You're a writer?
你是作家?
Yes.
是
I had no paper.
我没有纸
Papers for the bettor.
一张都没有
You're refugee?
你是难民?
Yes.
是
I'm a refugee.
我是个难民
Aja, this is so touching.
阿贾,这太感人了
Thank you.
谢谢
I was...I was overwhelmed by your story,
我被你的故事感动了
but it also helped me to understand a great deal.
同时也让我明白了很多事情
I sometimes feel blind,
我有时会"盲"然
just like your character.
就像你小说中的人物
Excuse me.
失陪一下
Good evening, Nelly.
下午好,Nelly
My God, you are beautiful.
天啊,你真漂亮
Beautiful, as always.
漂亮,一贯的漂亮
- Alfredo, the director is an idiot.  - No, no, no, no.
- Alfredo,导演是个白痴 - 不不不
Nelly, Michael Zhudovski is not an idiot, c'mon.
Nelly, Michael Zhudovski可不是白痴
He is an idiot.
他真的是
Yes, he's an idiot, but...
好吧,就算是,但...
Nelly, we have to finish this movie.
Nelly,我们得把戏拍完
If we don't finish this movie, I'm ruined.
要是我们不拍完这部戏,我就毁了
Please, help me.
拜托,请帮帮忙
The director is an idiot, but...
导演是个白痴,可...
Come have dinner, and we go out,
来吃晚饭,然后出去逛一圈
have a drink, just you and me.
喝点什么,就你跟我
We are divorced, Alfredo.
我们已经离婚了,Alfredo
You divorced me!
是你离的!
Nelly, please. We just need five days of re-shoots.
Nelly,拜托,我们只需要5天的重拍
No!
不!
I can't believe it. He is too young for you.
简直不能相信,他对你来说太年轻了
He's a writer
他是个作家
and an artist.
和艺术家
He wrote his last work on his shirt.
他上一部作品写在衣服上
Like the essence of Sufi poets.
就像古时候的诗人
On his shirt?
在他衣服上?
He didn't have any paper.
他没有纸
Isn't that a grand artistic gesture?
艺术家不都是这样的吗?
He took his shirt off his back
他脱下上衣
to write a story.
即兴写下了一个故事
Why would anyone do that?
为什么要这样?
It's art.
这是艺术
Art?
艺术?
Yes, art.
没错,是艺术
Nelly, that's not art.
Nelly,那根本不是艺术
Giancarlo wants to buy it.
Giancarlo就像买下它
Why are you talking to Giancarlo? What is it with Giancarlo?
你为啥跟Giancarlo说话? 这跟Giancarlo有毛关系?
He calls me.
他打给我的
Why does he call you?
他为啥打给你?
He calls.
反正就是打了
- Giancarlo wants to buy that?  - Yes.
- Giancarlo要买下它? - 是的
- How much?  - I can't say.
- 多少钱? - 我不能说
How much is he paying for the damn shirt?
买一件TMD衬衫能花多少钱?
Alfredo...
How much?
多少钱?
50.
€50,000 for a shirt?
5万欧元买个衬衫?
Well.
好吧
Let's get someone to send you up some clothes.
找点像样的衣服吧
Is your first time to Paris?
你是第一次来巴黎?
No, I lived here for 2 years.
不,我住这两年了
Please, tell me anything, anything I might do to make your trip more enjoyable.
有什么需要帮忙的,尽管跟我讲,我会尽力让你旅途更愉快
Something you want to talk about, something you want to know?
有啥想聊的,有啥想了解的,尽管讲
I have special gift.
我有个特别的天赋
I can read your future.
我能看相
- While you're driving?  - Yeah.
- 那你为啥还跑出租? - 是的
Some people read the future in tea leaves,
有些人能从喝的茶叶中读出未来
I read the future in traffic.
我呢,就能在出租车里读懂
What do you see?
那你能看出什么?
Right now, I see a trouble past.
目前,我读到你有痛苦的过去
Two years ago, I really messed up my life.
两年前,我确实生活一团糟
And now, I'm with a man who's really nice.
但现在,我认识一个男人,条件不错
I mean...
我意思...
To be honest, I don't even think it could get better.
说实话,我觉得无法再好了
He is creative,
他有创意
and he is handsome,
英俊
and he is gentle...
又有风度
He's planting flowers all over Paris.
他在巴黎做园艺
And now he is moving here for me.
现在甚至为了我搬过来定居
I got a lot of traffic here.
交通有点拥堵
And what does that mean?
什么意思?
There is someone else.
还有其他的男人
No, there's no one.
没有,没有别人
Traffic doesn't lie.
交通可不会撒谎
So, all you've done with this young woman is share a kiss?
所以说,你就吻过她一次而已?
I agree doesn't sound like much, but...
我知道那不算什么,但...
I can't stop thinking about her.
我无法停止想念她
You're in love.
那就是爱
Yes, I guess I'm in love.
没错,我想我恋爱了
Why did you divorce Alfredo?
你为啥跟Alfredo离婚?
The question should be "Why did I ever marry him?"
这个问题应该是"为什么我嫁给他?"
Why did you ever marry him?
那你为什么你嫁给他?
He was very handsome, exciting,
那时他很帅,充满活力
charming,
迷人
powerful, rich...
有权又有钱...
Suave and dangerous.
诱人又危险
Italian men can be very strange.
意大利男人很奇特
Then he changed?
后来他变了?
Not at all.
没变
That's why I divorced him.
所以跟他离婚了
Here!
这边!
I love this place.
我喜欢这里(我也去过吼吼)
It moves me how those coins represent
令我感动的是那些硬币代表着
the wishes and dreams of hundreds of people.
千万的梦想跟希望
I love that.
我好喜欢
A constellation of hopes and dreams.
一个充满梦想跟希望的星座
Okay, make a wish.
好吧,许个愿
I wish for money.
我梦想有钱
Throwing away money seems very counter-productive.
但扔进去是不是有违梦想
Okay.
好吧
- Yes!  - Huh, huh.
- 梦想成真! - 嗯
OK, my turn.
到我了
I wish...Thomas Grégoire could forgive me.
我希望...Thomas Grégoire能原谅我
Who's that?
那时谁?
Thomas Grégoire.
He was the love of my life,
是我一生致爱
a long, long time ago.
很久以前了
Even now, not one day passes by that I don't think of him.
时至今日,我没有一天不想着他
What happened?
发生了什么?
I became famous.
我成名了
I had an affair.
我出轨了
He found out in the newspapers.
他在报纸上知道了
It was on the front page of
我上了头版头条
every single newspapers on the planet.
全世界都在转载
And the reconciliation has to be just as spectacular.
所以,复合的话也会同样轰动
- What's your name?  - What?
- 你叫什么名字? - 什么?
What's your name?
你叫什么名字?
Aja!
阿贾
Ajatashatru Lavash Patel.
Are you and Nelly together?
你跟 Nelly 拍拖吗?
No. She's in love with the finest man in the world,
不是的,她爱的是一个世界上最完美的男人
Thomas Grégoire.
我爱你
Thomas Grégoire
I want that shirt!
那件衬衫我要了!
No, Alfredo.
不,Alfredo
You don't appreciate art.
你不懂欣赏艺术
How can you say I don't appreciate art?
你怎么这么说? 我不懂艺术?!
I appreciate art!
我懂艺术!
We promised Giancarlo.
我们都答应Giancarlo了的
Why Giancarlo?
为什么一定给Giancarlo?
Why always Giancarlo?! Why Giancarlo?
为什么总是Giancarlo?! 为什么?
So, how much are you offering?
那你准备出什么价?
€100,000.
10万欧元
Cash.
现金
她爱的是一个世界上最完美的男人
Thomas Grégoire
- Hi.  - Hi.
- 嗨 - 嗨
He called.
他打来电话了
Thomas called.
Thomas打电话了
谢谢你
- Alfredo  - Hi,Giancarlo
How's everything?
你还好吧?
Very good.
好得很
都很好
I heard Nelly's in town.
我听说Nelly来了
"You heard"?
"你听说"?
Huh, maybe, we could all have a drink?
嗯,或者我们可以一起喝一杯?
Of course, of course.
当然,当然可以
Please call me...
请给我电话...
or Nelly.
或者给Nelly都行
You... you...
你...你...
talked to her sometime?
有时也会联系她的反正
I mean,you called her?
我意思,你约她了?
Nelly?
No.
没呢
I'm sorry for the shirt.
关于那件衬衫,不好意思啦
What shirt?
什么衬衫?
The shirt-story.
写故事的衬衫
I bought the shirt.
我那衬衫买下了
What the hell are you talking about?
你到底在说啥呢?
I have to go.
我得走啦
Alfredo.
阿贾,你好!
Give me back the money.
把钱还给我
I said, "Give me back the money!"
我说"把钱还给我"
Okay, okay.
好的,好的
Moohini,where do I go?
牟尼,我该往哪跑?
- Hey, svelto (careful)  - Ciao, Francisco.
- 嗨,小心点 - 再见,Francisco
I flewed (flew) over Rome,
我飞过罗马
towards Paris.
直往巴黎
I even had provisions.
我还有机上配餐呢
I had time to dream
我还有时间梦想
about the terrific life that I would have with the money I had earned.
用这些赚来的钱过上美好的生活
Life was good.
生活真的美好
I traveled for hours and hours.
我飞了好久
It was beautiful.
风景如画
The winds seemed to be perfect.
风和日丽
I am a rich man!
I am a rich man...
我有钱啦...
and I am about to die.
但马上就要完蛋了
你好,需要服务吗?
Hello, this is the Indian Secretary of Commerce.
你好,我是印度商务部长
I need to talk to Marie.
我要跟Marie通话
- She is not in today, sir  - It's an emergency
- 她今天没在 - 有急事找她
Hello.
你好
Marie?
Marie's in a shower.
Marie在洗澡
This is Ajatashatru.
我是阿贾
You stood her up at the Eiffel Tower.
你在埃菲尔铁塔放她鸽子
No...
不是...
Yes, but...Can I leave a message?
是...能帮我留个话吗?
- Eh, yeah.  - Okay.
- 嗯,好吧 - 听着
I'm very, very sorry for missing our date for the Tower.
我非常抱歉错过了铁塔之约
Extraordinary circumstances made things difficult.
事出突然,一言难尽
I think, I may never be able to call her.
我可能再也见不到她了
Ever.
永远
I know we met only once...
我知道我们只一面之缘...
but our kiss was inspiring.
但我们一吻定情
Please tell her...
请跟她说...
Is she out of shower?
她洗完了吗?
- Uh, no.  - Okay.
- 嗯,还没 - 好吧
Please tell her if she never hears again from me...
若没有机会亲口跟她讲,请...
that...
转告她...
that I love him.
我爱她
Yes.
是真的
I will always, always, always love her.
我会永远永远永远爱她
I love her!
我爱她
She met someone else.
你慢了一步啦
And yesterday, they decided to move in together.
就在昨天,他们准备搬到一起生活
Can I change my message?
那帮我改一下留言吧
Sure.
好的
No message.
还是不留了
Aja, your life is a mess.
阿贾,你生活就是一团糟
You need to sort yourself and hurry back to Paris!
你得好好梳理好,赶紧回巴黎!
Listen to your mother, for once.
就好好听妈一次话
I know.
我知道
Just when my life seems to be getting back on track,
等我生活刚要回到正轨
Just when I get some money
等我攒够了钱
that might help me live a decent life,
让我能过上体面的生活
Just when love seems to be possible...
当爱成为可能
I am doomed to die an awful death.
可我就要死了
What kind of karma is that?
这是哪门子因果报应?
Stop blaming your karma, and take responsibility for your life!
别怪命运,你得自己掌握!
What do you mean?
你什么意思?
You are in control of your life,
你是自己生命的主宰
not chance, or karma.
而不是机会或者命运
Now, tell me.
好吧,跟我讲讲
What is in the briefcase?
箱子里有啥?
It's a long story.
说起来话长
I have all the time.
我有的是时间
I'm just trying to get to Paris.
我想去巴黎
Paris.
巴黎
You won't be there anytime soon.
我眼下还真去不了
We are going to Libya.
我们这是去利比亚的
- Libya?!  - Yes.
- 利比亚?! - 没错
And, what so precious in that briefcase that you won't let it go?
你箱子里有啥宝贝? 抱得这么紧
It's just some...
只不过是...
some of...
personal necessities.
Of course.
Open it.
Why? It's just some...
Open the briefcase.
What's with all the guns!
Indian,
open the briefcase!
Okay.
At that very moment,
I summoned
all my magical powers
to make the money
invisible.
Open the briefcase!
Libya had become the place that
it seemed all refugees ended up
at one point or another.
Aja.
Aja!
What are you doing in Africa, man?
What are you doing here?
Unfortunately, they don't want me
in the land of the milk and honey.
But I want to thank you.
I need your help.
There were several
clandestine refugee camps.
All people in transit.
I knew where the money was.
So I asked Wiraj if they could
help me get my briefcase back.
That was my money.
I had earned it.
There was no way
I would left the thief
steal my earnings.
I know exactly where my money is.
OK, but everyone,
no violence.
Understood?
Faysal,
no violence.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I want to go back to my wife.
How does someone
as ugly as you get a wife?
She doesn't care about the looks.
The hippo,
is as pretty as the gazelle,
in the eyes of his wife.
You can tell he's scared.
Raise it!
This moron thinks he can bluff me!
Shut up and put the money on the table!
The money!
Look at this!
What are you doing?
- Too violent?
- Yes.
Sorry.
Good evening, Aja.
Unfortunately,
tonight I'm in a very,
very bad mood.
Perfect. Let's go.
So,
how much do I owe you,
and others?
How much is in the briefcase?
- €2,000.
- €2,000!?
Well, as you know,
we're all in transit.
Many are running from the war?
Okay...
How much?
Whitman, lost his wife,
two years ago, in Mali.
Okay...
How much?
This side, Aziz,
must get to Germany
to find his twin brother.
Okay...
So, how...
How much?
Emel, there,
Emel.
She was attacked by soldiers
during the war.
A friend of her is in Brussels
owns bakery.
So she has a job waiting for her
only if she can get there.
Everyone of them has a dream.
I understand.
Give... what feels right.
A few of my brothers and sisters
helped me last night.
Anyone with a hope or a dream,
please stand in line.
I may be able to help you.
What is your wish?
To have a boat...
so I can go fish
at the sea to...
to earn money
for my family.
That seems very reasonable.
Buy your boat.
Feed your family.
Look!
Tell me.
I need a plane ticket
to Brussels.
I want to learn
how to make chocolate.
There you go.
Thank you.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
And then, it happened.
I couldn't stop.
I was overcome by
a feeling of well-being,
as if a lady in the clear vapor cloud
had appeared inside my chest
and was spreading
throughout my body.
In front of all these refugees,
I succeeded in creating
my greatest magic trick, ever.
How is that?
I transformed €2,000 into
a never ending flow of money.
People went back to their villages,
and everyone told the story of
Ajatashatru Lavash Patel.
Right then, I understood
what I really wanted.
I wanted to
come home to India.
I had just enough money
to buy my plane ticket
and a real fake passport.
But first, I had
one last important thing to do.
It's nice meeting you Aja.
Likewise.
Take care, man.
Safe trip.
Go, quick!
My money!
Honey, I'm sorry.
I'm late.
Traffic was terrible.
God damn-it,
I slaved away all day at work,
is it really too much
to ask for dinner to be ready?
It's lovely to see you.
It's lovely to see you too.
Marie,
I found the deck chair.
Oh, great.
Pieter, this is Aja.
Aja, this is Pieter.
Hi.
I'll see you soon.
Yeah.
€54, please.
This is a good deal
for a fabulous mother.
Thank you.
Only after this very difficult journey
that I realized
what I wanted in life.
Moohini!
You're still here.
How are you?
Wait...
Welcome home, Aja.
Eventually, I succeeding in
reaching a deal with Giri
to pay back the money he believed
I still owed him.
Then I started teaching.
Each morning, these kids show up
and I tell them stories.
And I make sure
their world becomes a bit bigger
and they understand
they are not poor.
The great poet
Rabindranath Tagore writes,
"How can you cross the sea
by merely standing and staring at it?"
What...
Well...
You boys, just think
what he means by that.
I'm sorry.
- I'm disturbing you.
- No, no.
I did promise.
Did you leave your fiancé
at the altar again?
Maybe I shouldn't have come.
Go back to your seats.
Now!
Go!
And that
is the end of the story.
Any questions?
What's a lesbian?
Someone who loves a woman.
So I can be a lesbian?
Well...
Yes.
Why did you say at the beginning
that this story was a tragedy?
You're going to prison
for four years.
That...
is a terrible tragedy.
You are going to lose
four of the best years of your life.
Unless...
you seize this opportunity.
What opportunity?
If you come to my
school every day,
you don't have to go to prison.
Really?
Really.
- Yes!
- Yes?
- Yes.
Yeah.
Every day.
- Every day.
Thank you, Aja.
Aja,
what about your mother?
Thank you so much for asking.
My mother is where
she always wanted to be.
Was that a true story?
Only the important parts.